（ナルト）あれは…。
十尾の人柱力だってばよ。
That's the Ten Tails'...
Jinchuriki!
The Ten Tails' Jinchuriki
十尾が消えた…。
The Ten Tails disappeared?
どうなってる　やっつけたのか？
What's going on?
Did they defeat it?
（ヒアシ）いや。
（サクラ）ヒナタ　見てた？
No...
Hinata! Did you see it?
（ヒナタ）うん。
何がどうなったのか説明できる？
Yeah!
Can you explain
what happened?
（ヒナタ）あの人に　十尾が
すべて吸収されてしまって…。
Ten Tails was completely
absorbed into that man.
チャクラから見ても…。
Based on looking at its chakra.
じゃあ　まさか…。
Don't tell me...
（サスケ）あれが　十尾の…。
That's the Ten Tails'...
人柱力だと？
Jinchuriki?
《扉間：な　なんだ　これは…》
What is this?!
《柱間：まずいのう
人柱力とは…》
This is bad.
Jinchuriki, huh?
ますます気味わりいってばよ。
He looks even creepier
than before!
（ミナト）オビト…。
Obito...
ナルト　なぜ　ヤツが人柱力だとわかる？
Naruto...
How can you tell
he's a Jinchuriki?
俺は　尾獣たちと仲よくなった。
I've become friends
with the Tailed Beasts.
そんとき　アイツらから
チャクラもらってっから　ハッキリわかる。
They gave me some
of their chakra earlier,
so it's obvious to me.
尾獣たちのチャクラが　次々　オビトの中へ
入っていったのを感じられた。
I could sense the Tailed Beasts' chakra
getting sucked into Obito
one after the other.
それに俺ってば長門が
六道の生き返りの術をするのを→
Plus, I've seen Nagato do that
Six Paths Rebirth Jutsu before.
１回見てる。
そもそも　術の印が全然違う。
But the signs he was weaving
were completely different!
とにかく　アイツは　はじめっから
人柱力になる術をしていたんだよ。
Anyway, he was performing
the jutsu
to become a Jinchuriki
all this time.
そうか。
I see...
《キラービー：八っつあんよ
あれが　最終形態か？》
Eight-o! Is that the final form?
（牛鬼）いや　違う。
ややこしいがあれじゃない。
No, it's not.
It's hard to explain,
but that isn't it.
どうやら　最終形態前で
人柱力に利用されやがった。
Looks like Ten Tails was
used to create a Jinchuriki
before it reached its final form.
フン！
《たとえ　人柱力になろうとも
明神門は継続中ぞ》
Even if you have become
a Jinchuriki,
the Gracious Deity Gates
are still in play.
Whoa! Amazing!
すげえ！
いや…。
No...
むっ！？
《十尾を止めていた
仙法の封印を…》
The Sage Art Seal that
suppressed the Ten Tails was...
《ヒルゼン：ここまでとは…》
Such power...
What?!
（ガイ）バカな…　あの四赤陽陣を！
Impossible!
The Four Crimson Rays Formation!
Is it just me,
でかいときより
強くなってねえか？
or is he stronger than
when he was gigantic?
気のせいか？
Before, it was just throwing
its power around.
ただ力を
ぶちまけるだけの前とは違う。
力を集中できるように
なったみてぇだ。
But now, it's learned to focus it.
（ヒアシ）皆の者　気を抜くな！
Everyone, keep your guard up!
向こうで十尾の力を
我がものとした輩が現れた！
We don't know what that man,
who made the Ten Tails' power
his own, might do!
何をするかわからぬぞ！
結界を壊しおった！
He's broken the barrier!
Enough! Obito, stop this!
やめろ　オビト！　もうやめるんだ！
O...bi...to?
（オビト）オ…　ビ…　ト？
はっきり言う。
こやつは俺より強い。
I'll be blunt.
This guy is stronger than me!
失礼ですが　そのようですな。
No offense,
but it appears so.
Even if you reabsorb
your remaining clones,
消え損ねた分身をよこしても
相手にならんぞ　兄者。
you're no match, Elder Brother!
わかっておる。
I know.
だが…。
However...
（マダラ）尻込みする火影どもが
見られるのは楽しいが→
It would be fun to watch
all the Hokage beg for mercy,
but I cannot wait any longer.
待ってもいられなくなったな。
Obito is now just like
the Sage of Six Paths.
《六道仙人と同じになったオビトだ。
I can't let him take the lead
before I use my trump card.
奥の手を使う前に
先を越されかねん》
えっ！
What's happened?
何だ！？
《速い！》
He's so fast!
Saru! Fourth! Scram!
サル　四代目！　飛べ！
《これは　二代目様の手順！》
This is Lord Second's attack plan!
– Elder Brother!
– Mm-hmm!
兄者！
うん！
EXPLODE
ミナトよ　離れるのじゃ！
Minato, get away!
二代目様は手が早い。
Lord Second,
you sure work fast!
《ミナト：飛雷神の術！》
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
やはり　この程度では死なんか。
I suspected that might
not be enough to kill you...
穢土転生の術は　わしが作った。
それに合った戦術もな。
I created the Reanimation Jutsu,
as well as ancillary jutsu
to go with it.
己の体でやるのは　初めてだが…。
Though this is the first time
I'm using it on myself.
《出るか？
二代目様考案の　互乗起爆札》
There it is!
The Lord Second's special...
Tandem Explosive Tags!
こうやるのだ！
This is how it's done!
《扉間：札が札を口寄せし続け
爆破を繰り返す…。
Each tag summons more tags,
resulting in continuous explosions.
Concentrated and focused
consecutive explosions!
連続一点集中の爆破だ！》
すごすぎるぜ！
もう　何がなんだか…。
This is too much!
What's going on? I can't keep up!
やけに　ならない！
常に　状況を見て。
Don't freak out!
Always keep one eye on
what's happening around you!
十尾の人柱力だろうが
なんだろうが→
I don't care if that is
the Jinchuriki of the Ten Tails!
火影様たちが戦っておられる。
The Lords Hokage are
engaged in battle!
We have to join them!
我々も行くぞ！
（ダルイ）焦るな！　今は…。
Don't be hasty! We need to—!
All of you!
You must not approach heedlessly!
皆の者！
うかつに近づいてはならん。
（ダルイ）なんだ？　アイツ…。
What is he?
《速いうえに堅い…。
He's solid and swift.
And he has an attack that
turns all to dust in an instant!
そして　一瞬で　塵にする攻撃！》
（ヒルゼン）手裏剣影分身！
Shuriken Shadow Clones!
It's similar to Ohnoki's Particle Style,
but its shape is fluid.
《オオノキの塵遁に似ているが→
形が流動的で　攻防に応じて変化し
常に保持できる》
It can shift to be either
offensive or defensive.
And can be continuously maintained.
ぐっ！
《おそらく　４つ以上の性質変化を
組み合わせている！
I suspect it's a combination of more
than four Changes in Chakra Nature!
This is more than a Kekkei Genkai
or even a Kekkei Touta...
血継限界　血継淘汰の　更に上！》
《だが　形態変化には
持続時間がありそうだのう》
But there seems to be
a time limit to how long
he can use each
Change in Chakra Form.
じいちゃん！
Gramps!
Dad! You couldn't teleport
Grandpa Third with your jutsu too?
父ちゃん　三代目のじいちゃんも
父ちゃんの術で→
飛ばせなかったのかよ！？
ムリだ。
It's impossible. I can't teleport
anything that I myself,
俺自身か俺のチャクラが　間接的にでも
触れていなければ　飛ばせない。
or my chakra isn't touching directly.
わめくな　ナルト！
火影たちは穢土転生だ。
Calm down, Naruto.
The Hokage are Reanimations.
死なないのを　わかっていて
敵の出方や能力を分析するため→
They intentionally attacked head-on
knowing that they won't die,
in order to check out
the enemy's moves and abilities.
あえて　突っ込んでいったんだ。
Stop worrying and analyze
the battle instead.
あの戦いを見て
心配より　分析をしろ！
《サスケ君か…　優秀な子だ》
So that's Sasuke...
He's extremely smart.
穢土転生が回復するまでには
少し　時間がかかるけどね。
Although it still takes a while
for a Reanimation to regenerate.
まずは　俺が出て　隙を作る！
I'll go first and create an opening!
At this point, I feel the need to...
こうなっては　やはり　俺が…。
I'm done waiting, Hashirama!
もう　待ったは　なしだ。　柱間！
な…　なんだ？
W-What's going on?
《そうか…　人柱力として　うまく
十尾が　なじんでないんだ。
I get it...
Ten Tails hasn't completely
synched with its Jinchuriki yet.
This is our chance to take it down!
この状況のうちに倒す！
オリジナルも　ここに！
I'll summon my original here then!
久しぶりの
螺旋閃光超輪舞吼参式をやる！》
It's been a while, but it's time
for my Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
Gamakichi! Below you!
ガマ吉　下だ！
（ガマ吉）ぐっ…。
うわっ！！
地面を通って…。
上半身だけを？
He passed underground!
It's just his upper body!
（ミナト）しまった…。
Damn it!
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
お前じゃない。
You're not the one...
過去を切るのは…　俺だ。
...who's going to sever the past. I am!
間に合え…。
I hope this makes it in time!
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
《飛雷神の術！
オビトのマーキングが消えている！？》
My markings on Obito disappeared?
ク…　クソッ…。
Damn it!
Owww...
（ガマ吉）アイテテテテ…。
ひぃ…　死ぬかと思ったってばよ。
I thought we were going to die!
((俺自身か　俺のチャクラが→
I can't teleport anything
that I myself,
(間接的にでも
触れていなければ飛ばせない))
or my chakra isn't
touching directly.
《ミナト：フフッ…　うちの子も
サスケ君に負けていないかな。
Looks like my boy is
as accomplished as Sasuke.
さて…》
Now then...
（ガマ吉）まるで蛇じゃな。
He's just like a snake.
What is that?
何だ？　あれ…。
We have to take him down
体を　うまく扱えてない。
今のうちに　やらないと。
while he's still unable
to use his body well.
くっ…　あぁっ…。
うっ…　うぅっ…。
今　父ちゃんの分身を狙ったのか？
Was he after your clone
just now, Dad?
いや　どうも
そんな感じじゃなかった。
No, I don't think that was it...
なんだ？　どうしたんだ？
What? What happened?!
自分の技を　くらってやがる。
He hit himself with his own attack.
攻撃は外れたんだ。
大きすぎる十尾の力に→
His attack missed.
Seems Obito's consciousness
is merely clinging
オビトの意識が　どうにか
へばりついているだけで→
to Ten Tail's great power.
まるで　コントロールできていない。
He barely has any control over it.
外れたけん　ええけど…
くろうたら死ぬるのう…。
I'm glad he missed us,
because if it hit us,
we'd be dead!
うかつには近づけんで…。
We can't approach him carelessly.
今度こそ
螺旋閃光超輪舞吼参式をやる！
This time, I'll get
the Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three in for sure!
隙を作るから　カンパツいれずに→
I'll create an opening,
so you two hit him immediately
with your strongest combo!
お前たちのコンビ技を
叩き込むんだよ！
リン…。
Rin...
ぐあぁ！
((もちろん
俺は火影になんぜ！))
Of course,
I'm going to be the Hokage!
リン…。
Rin!
((そしたら　女にかまけてる
時間なんか　ねえんだよ。
And then...
I won't have any time for girls!
(だろ？　先生))
Right, Sensei?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
いくよ　オビト。
Here I come, Obito!
お前…　誰…。
Who...are...you?
うおぉっ！
やっとだよ。　先生。
Finally, Sensei...
《ヤバイ！》
Damn it!
父ちゃん！
ナルト！　構えろ！
Dad!
Naruto, focus!
やられはしたけど大丈夫。
He got me, but I'm okay!
飛雷神で飛んだから。
I used Flying Raijin to escape.
どうかな？
Are you sure about that?
《いつの間に！？
そうか　俺につけて一緒に…》
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
２時間スペシャル！